MINGYI LIN

 \boxtimes

iamyle0710@gmail.com



(+1) 213-275-9974



https://www.linkedin.com/in/mingyiericlin/



https://github.com/iamyle0710

*

https://iamyle0710.github.io/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jul 2020 - Present

Web Application Developer

Stamps.com Inc. — El Segundo, United States

Rebuild the legacy Stamps.com "Products" application

Maintain, enhance and optimize all Stamps.com applications

TECHNOLOGIES: Javascript React PrimeReact

May 2019 - May 2020

Frontend Developer (Student Worker)

Information Sciences Institute — Los Angeles, United States

Increased code readibility and scalability of a cell-research web application by refactoring entire code structure and incorporating features that let users annotate microscopic images

Collaborated with the team to extend E2E testing scripts using Protractor

TECHNOLOGIES: Javascript D3.js AngularJS Protractor Bootstrap

Oct 2014 - July 2018

Frontend Engineer

Chunghwa Telecom Laboratories — Taiwan

Increased the speed at which civilian reports are relayed to emergency responders by building a dashboard application, which provided users a geographical visualization of emergent reports in real time

Saved 15% of the energy consumption of a client's premises from year 2016 to 2017 by developing auto-control IoT equipment features

Monitored up to 50,000 pieces of IoT equipment with less than 3 seconds response time on web application, which reduced 30% of server loading

TECHNOLOGIES: C# Javascript jQuery Node.js MQTT

PROJECTS

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

LA Metro Bike Data Visualization

Led a team of three members and developed a dashboard application using Angular which analyzes/visualizes metro-bike usage performance

Strengthened insights from the data with interactive statistic charts

TECHNOLOGIES: Javascript Angular Bootstrap Python

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

Pot of Cha - User interface Design and Usability Testing

Conducted 10+ user interviews to find primary persona and generalized user stories, goal-directed user scenario and user cases

Demostrated a well-designed portfolio with sitemap, wireframes, visual design and prototypes using Sketch and Principle

TECHNOLOGIES: Sketch Principle

Oct 2018 - Jan 2019

Oriole - Pitch Detector

Led a team of two members to build a web application to creatively detect users' vocal range and filters songs that match the determined range

Reduced the web processing tasks by using Python to extract songs metadata and pitch range. Saved data in NoSQL database

TECHNOLOGIES: Javascript React Python Firebase

SUMMARY

I'm currently a web application developer at Stamps.com. I have over 5 years industry experience. I am experienced in developing single-page web applications using different web technologies, and I have a strong sense for aesthetics and user interaction.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Javascript Python

WEB TECHNOLOGIES

HTML5 CSS3 D3.js Bootstrap

Angular React Redux jQuery

Sketch Principle

DATABASE TECHNOLOGIES

MySQL Firebase MQTT

TOOLS

Spark MapReduce Git

EDUCATION

University of Southern California

M.S. in Data Science

GPA: 4.0 / 4.0

National Central University

M.B.A. in Information Management

GPA: 4.0 / 4.0

Tatung University

B.B.A. in Information Management

GPA: 3.7 / 4.0